BDUL NAEEM LATIFY ORANGE COUNTY, ANAHEIM, CALIFORNIA





CONTACT

714-650-7598

anlatify@skype.com

□ anlatify@live.com

PROFILE

Bringing over 5 years of experience in Information technologies with 3 years of experience in System Administration and Troubleshooting, Network management include, Audits, Implementation, Administration, Analyses, Operation & troubleshoots with a solid management skill, capable of leading and motivating individuals to maximize levels of productivity, while forming cohesive team environments. Exceptional communicator focused on building strong client relationships.

SKILLS

- MICROSOFT WINDOWS **SERVER**
- **ACTIVE DIRECTORY**
- **OPERATING SYSTEMS**
- INFORMATION SECURITY
- DISASTER RECOVERY
- **NETWORK MONITORING**
- **USERS/GROUP POLICIES**
- DNS/DHCP SERVICES.
- **VOIP SERVICES**
- LINK AGGREGATION
- ROUTING
- **SWITCHING**
- COMPUTER IMAGING
- PC/NETWORK SECURITY
- CISCO ROUTERS/SWITCHES COUNFIGURATION

EXPERIENCE

Arcadia Chair Company

August, 2018 to Present

Monitor and Respond to All Help Desk Requests in a Professional, Thorough and

Provide Technical Support for Issues Related to IT Systems, Phone Systems, Software and Hardware

Resolve Routine Office IT Issues Including Phone, Fax, Printer, AV, Access Control and Email Issues

Assist Remote Employees through screen connect software

Thoroughly Document Internal Procedures

Provide network technical support, routing, switching, Trucking, and Port

Aggregation/port channel in Cisco nexus 3000 series switches

Conduct Staff Training

Set Up New Employees, Domain User account, password, email, and profile Suggest Possible Improvements on Procedures

Report Significant and Recurring Issues for Higher Level of Support

Working on imaging software (Macrium)

ICT Specialist in WB/CCNPP

2016-2018

Troubleshoot and support local network, remote office networks, and WAN connections between office and Client home computer,

Assist with updating/maintaining current policies, procedures and other documentation

Maintain and troubleshoot servers, firewalls, network appliances, and Monitor

Maintain and troubleshoot critical software and monitor backup applications Monitor and maintain anti-virus, anti-spam and patch management applications Assist with user onboarding

Maintain phone system, including moving phones, setting up voice mail. Maintain other equipment, including mobile devices and AV equipment Assist with planning and preparing and implementing new projects

- SERVERS MAINTENANCE/
 ADMINISTRATION
- PATCH MANAGEMENT
- FIREWALLCONFIGURATION
- CLOUD COMPUTING
- PC/SERVERSTROUBLESHOOT
- TICKETING
- DOCUMENTATIONS

EDUCATION

Fullerton College

January 2020 to Present

Computer Science

Mashal University

2014 - 2018

Bachelor in Business Administration.

Alkhozarwia High School

2008

CERTIFICATION

CompTIA A+

CompTIA Network+

CompTIA Operations Specialist

ICSI | CNSS (Certified Network Security Specialist)

MCP: Microsoft Certified Professional

Coursera: System Administration and IT

Services

Coursera: Cloud Platform Fundamentals:

Core Infrastructure

Perform current state analysis of client systems, provide documentation and recommendations based on project scope

Assist with Installation and configuration of enterprise-level software Effectively troubleshoot software issues, and perform research for resolution

IT Officer Asian Development Bank

2014-2016

Provide timely support and serve as the primary contact for critical and high application/network-based outages

Provide support to users and troubleshoots/resolves problem

Maintain computers, networks, printers, WIFI access point, servers, security cameras etc.

Create/administer/troubleshoot active directory users/group policies Plan, coordinate and implement server installations, upgrades, and routine maintenance and prioritize and respond to issues as needed

Monitor and tune systems to achieve optimum performance levels provide performance statistics and reports.

Define and perform server backups and recovery procedures

Participate in development, testing, and implementation of business continuity and disaster recovery plans

Collaborate and coordinate with other functional areas within IT to ensure reliability of IT infrastructure and Security.

Manage and administer Networking system, Switches, Routers, and firewall.

IT Officer Afghan United Bank

2012 - 2013

Provide Support to end-users with IT-related problems in a responsive and service-oriented manner.

Install, configure and maintain windows server operating systems,

configure and maintain Microsoft Active Directory, DNS and DHCP, WSUS, services, Setup, management, and maintenance of IT-related equipment.

Monitor backup jobs and ensure high level of completion success rate.

Help processes in place to maintain a stable network environment.

Assist the IT director with project work to grow the technology infrastructure of the organization.

Provide troubleshooting, installation, and implementation of systems.

Ensure data integrity with regard to our fixed asset inventories.

Provide input and recommendations to the organization surrounding hardware and software processes.

IT Specialist USAID/ Agriculture Credit Enhancement 2010 – 2012

Internet protocols and services DNS, DHCP, CDN, IPv4 and IPv6
Advanced routing and network configurations including VLAN's, QoS, Wire Shark,
Active Directory construction and maintenance including OU/Groups/User
management, AD Group Policy creation, assignment and troubleshooting
Windows file and folder security and permissions

Server Role planning, installation, management and troubleshooting. DNS, DHCP, File/Print,

Server Application planning, installation, management and troubleshooting Cloud service implementation, migration and management